# Noémie Tapie

User Experience Researcher & Designer

Portfolio LinkedIn

User Research Prototyping User Testing Redesign

Team player Creative thinking Communication

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am Noémie, a professional UX researcher with dual Master's degrees in Human Factors from two prestigious universities.

I maximize your company's benefits by bringing genuine user insights and data-driven strategies. I tailor my approach to each project, drawing from my collection of over 40 user-centered methods and creating interfaces that truly meet your users' needs.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# THALES UX RESEARCHER & DESIGNER

February 2024 - now

THALES - INNOVATION & GREEN OPERATIONS

 UX research and design of a collaborative application for flight dispatchers, aiming at optimizing the fuel costs of flights by 5 to 10%.

#### LÍSH р

# **USER EXPERIENCE RESEARCHER**

May - August 2023

LABORATOIRE INTERDISCIPLINAIRE DES SCIENCES DU NUMERIQUE

- Organisation of the workflow of a multi actor and collaborative publishing tool.
- Conducting user experience research (Interviews, breakdown analysis, persona, user groups, user journey map)
- Prototyping of the intial interactions and preparing workshops to test them.
- Redesigning the interactions on Protopie

Supervisor - Michel Beaudoin-Lafon

External contact - Nicolas Taffin

Note - Participation in illustrating examples for a novel design methods publication by Wendy Mackay

#### statista 🗹

# PRESENTATION DESIGNER

2020 - 2022

**STATISTA** 

- Design of statistics and powerpoint
- Communication with all members of the publication workflow
- Training of new team members
- Occasional design of posters and flyers for company events.

#### **CUSTOMER SERVICE**

2018 - 2020

# **LANGUAGES**

French - native English - fluent (TOEFL) German - fluent (Test DAF)

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- analytical
- problem solving
- self-organized
- structured
- motivated
- team player
- communicator
- creative thinking,
- curious
- open minded

# HARD SKILLS

- Protopie, Figma
- Miro, Notion, Trello, Office 365, Pitch
- Unity, Blender, Shapr3D
- Illustrator, Photoshop, Filmora, Powerpoint
- VSCode, GitHub
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, Python, Flutter
- Design Thinking
- User Research, Prototyping, User Testing, Redesing
- Psychology, sociology

#### **INTERESTS**

- Dancing, visiting friends, travelling, playing games, hiking, singing, cooking,
- Ethical and philosophical concerns, environment, well-being, inclusivity

# **EDUCATION**



# M. Sc. HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION AND DESIGN



EIT Digital double degree, 2022 - 2024 Aalto University, Finland Université Paris-Saclay, France



#### **B. Sc. HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION**

Hamburg University, 2018 - 2022, Germany

# PROGRAMS AND DISTINCTIONS



#### **DUBSTECH PROTOTHON 2024**

UX Hackathon, 2024, University of Washington



#### INTERNATIONAL ADVISOR

Athene Guild, Aalto, 2024, Finland



# **GROUP LEAD VOLUNTEER AREA**

SLUSH, Start-up event, 2023, Finland



#### AI AND DIGITAL WELLBEING

EIT Digital Summer School, 2023, Lithuania



#### XR AND E-HEALTH

EUGLOH Summer School, 2023, Germany, first place



# AirBus GameJam

Airbus hackahton, 2021, Germany



#### **EuVsVirus**

Pan-European Hackathon, 2020



# **EXPO 2020**

Campus exhibition, Germany, 2020, third place